Guide to the Vassar College Dean of the College, Dean of the Faculty Records, 1917-1997 (bulk 1940-1996
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Guide to the Vassar College Dean of the College, Dean of the Faculty Records
1917-1997
1940-1996
Vassar College Dean of the College, Dean of the Faculty
153 cubic feet (153 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Materials relating to admissions, campus facilities, curriculum development, departmental policy, events, faculty oversight and reviews, general administration, grant proposals and student life.
Administrative History
In 1913 Vassar established the position of Dean, which was filled by Ella McCaleb, previously the Secretary of the College. Reporting directly to the President, the Dean was considered the executive officer of the faculty and was responsible for overseeing 11 offices, 26 academic departments, 8 programs and college admissons, as well as developing and refining educational policy. Due to the Dean’s broad scope of responsibilities, between 1915 and 1984 the position changed official titles numerous times. One notable change occurred in 1962 when the position was divided into the Dean of the Faculty, which Marion Tait filled, and Dean of Studies. The Dean of the Faculty was elected for a five year term by a faculty committee with approval from the Board of Trustees and the President. In 1981 the Dean of the Facutly position was replaced by that of Dean of the College; however, in 1991 the Office of the Dean of the Faculty was reestablished and resumed its role as Vassar’s chief academic officer. In 1994 the Office of the Dean of the College was created in order to reconsolidate many of the student oriented administrative offices and services that had been divided since the separation of the Dean of the Faculty and Dean of Studies in 1962.
Chronology
1913 The position of Dean of the College was established at Vassar College.
1962 Dean of the College position was divided into the Dean of the Faculty and Dean of Studies.
1981 Dean of the Facutly position was replaced by that of Dean of the College.
1991 Office of the Dean of the Faculty was reestablished.
1994 Office of the Dean of the College was created.
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes correspondence, memoranda, minutes, questionnaires, reports and surveys relating to admissions, campus facilities, curriculum development, departmental policy, events, faculty oversight and reviews, general administration, grant proposals and material related to student life during the 1940s through the 1990s. Topics of note include the decision for Vassar to become co-educational; construction and renovation of various campus buildings including the library, the Seely G. Mudd Chemistry Building and the Sanders classroom; the establishment of new departments including Black Studies and Science, Technology and Society; proposals for grants including the Matthew Vassar Lecture Fund, the Novy Fund, the Mellon Foundation, the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH), and the National Science Foundation (NSF); minutes from the Committee on Curricular Policy and Board of Trustees; and the annual reports for numerous academic departments.
Access
Because the collection has not been fully processed, access is restricted. Please contact the Archives and Special Collections staff for further information.
Related Materials
Vassar College Dean of the College Records
Vassar College Dean of the Faculty Records
Subject Headings
Names:
Organizations:
Vassar College--Administration; Vassar College--Admission; Vassar College. Board of Trustees; Vassar College--Faculty; Vassar College--Students
Subjects:
Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie
VCL Categories
Vassar College Administrative Offices and Functions
Encoding Information
Encoded by Ashley Todd and Laura Streett, August 2010 and May 2011.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in the original order in which it was received.
Container List
- Loose Victorian Studies Papers, 1987 (Box 1)
- Garsney Fund, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
- FPCC, Jan 1986 - June 1986 (Box 1)
- FPCC, Sep 1984 - Dec 1985 (Box 1)
- Department Chairs, 1986-1988 (Box 1)
- Department Chairs MS List (Box 1)
- Division Meetings, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
- Collections Manager Candidates (Box 1)
- Interdepartmental (Box 1)
- Medieval Studies, n.d. - 1985 (Box 1)
- SILP, 1985 (Box 1)
- "Black Experience" Course (Box 1)
- Drama, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
- Budget - Trip, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
- Art Department, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
- Anthropology (Box 1)
- Teaching Load Questionnaire Replies (Box 1)
- Faculty Tenure (Box 1)
- Faculty Tenure Correspondence, 1974-1987 (Box 1)
- House Fellows Manual, 1971, revised 1981 (Box 1)
- Mid-Hudson MLA (Box 1)
- Minority and Special Students, 1979-1983 (Box 1)
- New England Deans' Meeting, 1984-1989; (2 folders) (Box 1)
- NY Times Edward Fiske Guide, 1982-1986 (Box 1)
- Northeast Region Deans' [Meeting], 1982-1986 (Box 1)
- Nursery School, 1984-1988; (4 folders) (Box 1)
- Library Automation, 1986-1988; (2 folders) (Box 1)
- Library Budget Resolution, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
- Board of Trustees Executive Committee Minutes, Sep 1974- May 1981; (22 folders) (Box 2)
- Files [sent] to Storage [in] 1989: AAVC/Alumnae/i Association of Vassar College, Jan 1983 - June 1986 (Box 2)
- AAVC/Alumnae/i Association of Vassar College, 1980-1982 (Box 2)
- General Correspondence: Academic calendars, correspondence, etc., 1980-1984 (Box 2)
- Library Long-Range Planning, 1978-1983 (Box 2)
- Academic Computer Center, Various Correspondence with D. Spicer, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
- Computer literacy proposal, EDUCOM Consultant, 1981 (Box 2)
- Academic program development/ summer sessions, 1981-1985 (Box 3)
- Academic Resource Center, general, 1982-1987 (Box 3)
- Academic Resource Center, 1979-1982 (Box 3)
- Adelphi University, 1974-1982 (Box 3)
- Administrative reorganization, 1968-1983 (Box 3)
- Admissions, General Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
- Admissions, General Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
- Admissions, General Correspondence, 1984 (Box 3)
- Admissions, General Correspondence, 1983 (Box 3)
- Admissions, General Correspondence, 1982 (Box 3)
- Advisor to minority and special students, 1981-1987 (Box 3)
- Pre-major advising, 1979-1983 (Box 3)
- Affirmative Action, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
- American Association for the Advancement of the Humanities, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
- Association of American Colleges, 1980-1987 (Box 3)
- Audio visual center, 1977-1986 (Box 3)
- Files [sent] to Storage [in] 1989: Associate Dean Chron, general correspondence - P. Johnson, 1983-1987; (4 folders) (Box 3)
- Faculty Handbook, 1981-1983; (2 folders) (Box 3)
- Faculty Handbook Revision Committee, 1984 (Box 3)
- Career Development, 1984-1986 (Box 4)
- Nursery School, 1980-1984; (2 folders) (Box 4)
- Critical Language Program, 1982 (Box 4)
- Workload Study, 1984 (Box 4)
- ICEC, 1984-1986 (Box 4)
- Sharai Sweet, 8 May 1986 (Box 4)
- Faculty Publications and Professional Activities, 1980-1985 (Box 4)
- IBM Secondary School Program, 1984 (Box 4)
- Cambridge Assoc, Financial Equilibrium Study, 1981 (Box 4)
- Bryn Mawr College - Academic Computer Center (Box 4)
- Library Files, 1982-1986; (2 folders) (Box 4)
- Academic Computer Center, 1982-1987; (2 folders) (Box 4)
- Center for Career Development and Field Work, 1980-1984, 1986-1987; (4 folders) (Box 4)
- Task Force on Teaching Symposium, 1982-1985; (3 folders) (Box 4)
- Faculty Members Willing to Speak at Symposium (Box 4)
- Sophomore Parents Weekend - General Correspondence (Box 4)
- 7 Sisters College Conference, 1950-1961, 1963; (4 folders) (Box 4)
- Security, 1975-1985; (2 folders) (Box 5)
- Safety Committee, Radiation, VDT's, etc. (Box 5)
- Science Equipment (Box 5)
- Retirement Policies (Box 5)
- Registrar, 1980-1987; (3 folders) (Box 5)
- Questionnaires, 1975-1989; (3 folders) (Box 5)
- Personnel, 1981-1988; (3 folders) (Box 5)
- Oberlin Science Conference [personnel], 1984, 1986; (3 folders) (Box 5)
- Oberlin Group Questionnaire (Box 5)
- Oberlin Report, 1985 (Box 5)
- Oberlin Group Liberal Arts Forum, 1986 (Box 5)
- Ad Hoc Committee, 1971 (Box 5)
- Board of Trustees Exec. Comm. Minutes, 1971 (Box 5)
- Board of Trustees Exec. Comm. Minutes, 1972-1974 (Box 6)
- Board of Trustees Exec. Comm. Minutes, 1948-1961, 1968-1971 (Box 6)
- College Course Correspondence, 1980-1986; (2 folders) (Box 7)
- CCP Minutes, 1976-1980 (Box 7)
- CCP - Curricular Changes Made During, 1976-1982; (17 folders) (Box 7)
- Trustee Common Minority Affairs etc., ca. 1970-1989 (Box 8)
- Committee on Research, 1986-1987; (2 folders) (Box 8)
- Development, 1980-1986; (4 folders) (Box 8)
- Vassar Today, 1983-1987 (Box 8)
- Faculty Housing, 1960-1983; (2 folders) (Box 8)
- Faculty Leaves, 1978-1987; (3 folders) (Box 8)
- Workload: Teaching Assignments (Box 8)
- Faculty Workload - General (Box 8)
- Faculty Load, 1980-1981, 1979-1980 "A"; (2 folders) (Box 8)
- Teaching Load (Chairman's Responses), Dec 1978 (Box 8)
- Course Enrollment Figures, 1979-1978 (Box 8)
- Center for Integrative Studies, 1984 (Box 8)
- Visiting Committee Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 8)
- College Venture Prog. Correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box 8)
- Unscrewed Correspondence, 1980-1987 (Box 8)
- CCP, Sep 1969 - May 1974 (Box 9)
- CCP - Curricular Changes, 1983-1986; (4 folders) (Box 9)
- Opening Days, 1986-1989 (Box 9)
- CCP (Box 9)
- CCP - Original Minutes, 1983-1984; ( 3 folders) (Box 9)
- CCP - Original Minutes, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
- "As They See It" by Alice Howson: Vassar Freshmen and Higher Learning, 1977; (2 folders) (Box 10)
- Anthropology Departmental Files, 1980-1983; (4 folders) (Box 10)
- CCP Quality of Education at Vassar, 1974-1980; (2 folders) (Box 10)
- CCP Leaves and Privileges Committee, 1967-1985 (Box 10)
- CCP Schedule of Classes, Dec 1968 - Oct 1972 (Box 10)
- Set #6: 18 pieces of task force materials for CCP (Box 10)
- CCP Comprehensive Plan, 1967-1971; (2 folders) (Box 10)
- Board of Trustees, 1983-1988; (4 folders) (Box 10)
- Graves, Michael Architect Taylor Hall (Box 10)
- Questionnaires, 1976-1986; (2 folders) (Box 10)
- Ammerican Culture, art, annual reports, 1973-1978 (Box 10)
- Art Gallery, 1987-1988; (2 folders) (Box 11)
- Committee on Research, (2 folders) (Box 11)
- Multidisciplinary Project: American Culture (Box 11)
- Art Dept., Jan 1971 - June 1976; (2 folders) (Box 11)
- Art Dept. [personnel], 1969-1970 (Box 11)
- Anthropology - Sociology, Jan 1972 - June 1976; (2 folders) (Box 11)
- Art Dept. [personnel], 1965-1968; (2 folders) (Box 11)
- CCP, Course Changes, 1974-1976; (3 folders) (11)
- CCP, Course Changes, 1968-1975; (16 folders) (Box 12)
- CCP, Minutes, 1944-1957; (6 folders) (Box 12)
- CCP, Minutes, 1957-1969; (11 folders) (Box 13)
- Files [sent] to Storage [in] 1989: All College Symposia, 1982-1986 (Box 13)
- Dean of Studies, 1976-1985; (2 folders) (Box 13)
- Project "84,", (2 folders) (Box 13)
- Art Gallery, 1985-1986; (2 folders) (Box 13)
- Annual Reports to the Dean, 1970-1978 (Box 14)
- Select file, ACHMA (Assoc. Colleges of Mid-Hudson Area), 1964 (Box 14)
- Recruitment/Advertisements, 1982-1986; (5 folders) (Box 14)
- Registrar, 1982-1985 (Box 14)
- CCP, Faculty Notices, 1966-1975; (4 folders) (Box 14)
- CCP, Minutes, 1969-1976; (10 folders) (Box 14)
- CCP, Minutes, 1967-1969; (2 folders) (Box 15)
- CCP, Miscellaneous, 1967-1975; (5 folders) (Box 15)
- Sitomer Fund, 1985-1987 (Box 15)
- Files in Storage: Louise Boyle Fund D-53 (Box 15)
- Evelyn Clark Conference/Symposium (Box 15)
- Fulbright (Box 15)
- Grant Proposals (Box 15)
- Grant Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 15)
- Grants - IBM (Box 15)
- HEW Grants (Box 15)
- NSF Grants, 1986-1987 (Box 15)
- National Endowment for the Humanities- News Releases (Box 15)
- Mellon Grant Proposal, 1985-1986 (Box 15)
- Grants - HEW Special Services (Box 15)
- HEGIS Report, 1981-1982 (Box 15)
- HEGIS, [personnel], 1978-1980 (Box 15)
- Material - HEDS/HEGIS, 1979-1980 (Box 15)
- HEGIS/AAUP (Box 16)
- NYSED Report - Faculty Salaries [personnel], 1976-1977 (Box 16)
- Grants - General (Box 16)
- Kellog Application, 1982-1983; (16 folders) (Box 16)
- Grants- Lily Endowment, Inc. (Box 16)
- Grants - Japan Foundation, 1987 (Box 16)
- Grants - Information Sheets, 1979 (Box 16)
- Files to Storage [IN] 1988: Deans Budgets, [personnel], 1949-1969 (Box 16)
- Faculty Salary Budgets [personnel], 1959-1964, 1970-1978; (4 folders) (Box 16)
- Faculty Salary Budget Recommendations [personnel], 1963-1964 (Box 16)
- Departmental Budgets [personnel], 1966-1969; (2 folders) (Box 16)
- Vassar College Budget [personnel], 1963-1967; (2 folders) (Box 16)
- Vassar - Yale New Dimensions - Student Questionnaire (Box 17)
- State Master Plan Materials and Progress Report, 1972-1978; (6 folders) (Box 17)
- Bermuda College Plan, 1976 (Box 17)
- Poughkeepsie Day School (Various Reports and Files), 1969-1984; (4 folders) (Box 17)
- Opening Days, 1984-1986 (Box 17)
- NYS Ed Certification [personnel], 1970-1979 (Box 17)
- Files in Storage: Grants - National Endowment for the Arts [personnel] (Box 17)
- Mellon Fellowships in the Humanities (Box 17)
- Mellon Grants - Reports/Awards Received, 1985 (Box 17)
- Mellon Grants - Second Round, 1985-1986 (Box 17)
- Mellon Grants - First Round, 1986-1987 (Box 17)
- Mellon Grants Second Round, 1986-1987 (Box 17)
- Mellon Grants - Second Round, 1987-1988 (Box 17)
- Mellon Grants - First Round, 1985-1986 (Box 17)
- Mellon Grant, 1982-1983; (5 folders) (Box 17)
- Award Letters, 1983 (Box 18)
- Sloan Foundation - Cognitive Science, ca. 1980-1985 (Box 18)
- New Liberal Arts Program Progress Report (Box 18)
- Grants - Research Corporation (Box 18)
- Presidential Discretionary Fund (Box 18)
- Grants - PEW Foundation (Box 18)
- Grants NASA-AMES University Consortium (Box 18)
- New York State Health Research Conclusions (Box 18)
- New York State Education Department - Program Grants (Box 18)
- Mellon Grant Proposal, 1985-1986; (2 folders) (Box 18)
- Matthew Vassar Lecture Fund, 1986-1987 (Box 18)
- Novy Fund, 1986-1987 (Box 18)
- Zimand Fund, 1978-1985; (6 folders) (Box 18)
- Zimand Budget Records, 1980-1982; (2 folders) (Box 18)
- Zimand Correspondence, General (Box 18)
- Academic Resource Center, (3 folders) (Box 18)
- Faculty Student Ratios (Box 18)
- Report on Men's Education, annotated, 23 May 1968 (Box 18)
- Report to Mellon: Process of Education at Vassar, 1950 (Box 18)
- Report on Men's Education, 1968 (Box 18)
- Consumer's Guide to Vassar College, 1974 (Box 18)
- "A Program for Data Processing,", 1964 (Box 18)
- "An Analysis of the Data Processing Requirement for Education and Research,", 1965 (Box 18)
- Committee on Admission Annual Reports, 1950-1958 (Box 18)
- Special Report on Admission, 1974 (Box 18)
- Ecological Field Station (Box 19)
- Endowed Funds, B, D, E and F, 1981 (Box 19)
- Documents Pertaining to the Program of the College Research Center, Prepared for Mrs. Alvin C. Eurich, 1967 (Box 19)
- Dean of Studies (Box 19)
- Day Care Center (Box 19)
- CIES (Box 19)
- Convocation (Box 19)
- Copy Center (Box 19)
- Conferences/Meetings - Outside Organizations (Box 19)
- Jodi Sanfort (Box 19)
- Trustee Lists, 1977-1988; (2 folders) (Box 19)
- Faculty Meetings, 1979-1985, 1987-1988; (2 folders) (Box 19)
- Vassar College Historian (Box 19)
- Taskforce on Teaching (Box 19)
- VSA (Box 19)
- Vassar-Wesleyan Program in Spain (Box 19)
- Tuition Remission (Box 19)
- Telephones (Box 19)
- Taskforce on Teaching Evaluation (Box 19)
- Teaching Assignments, 1985-1987 (Box 19)
- AAUP (Box 19)
- AAA - Vassar College (Box 19)
- Academic Computer Center, 1987-1988 (Box 19)
- VC Reports on Officers Issue, annotated, Dec 1962 (Box 19)
- MSA: Final Draft (Box 19)
- Report on Self-Evaluation by VC for MSA, Dec 1957 (Box 19)
- MSA: Report of the Evaluation of VC, dean's office file copy, Mar 1958 (Box 19)
- MSA: Report of the Evaluation of VC, Marion Tate's copy, annotated, Mar 1958 (Box 19)
- American Council on Education, 1980-1985 (Box 20)
- Handicapped (HEW), 1980-1982 (Box 20)
- Suffrage, 1973-1974, 1986-1987 (Box 20)
- Residence, 1979-1980, 1985-1986 (Box 20)
- Seven Sister Colleges, 1980-1984 (Box 20)
- Miscellaneous, 1982-1985 (Box 20)
- Registrar, 1984-1987 (Box 20)
- SAC, 1984-1987 (Box 20)
- Purchasing, 1980-1987 (Box 20)
- Presidential Search Committee, 1985 (Box 20)
- Campus Communications - Post Office, 1975-1988 (Box 20)
- Phi Beta Kappa, 1982-1987 (Box 20)
- Affirmative Action Report - Hunter College (Box 20)
- Dean of Studies, 1985-1987; (2 folders) (Box 20)
- Heat (Box 20)
- Residential Life (Box 20)
- Summer Programs and Conferences (Box 20)
- Prizes: The DeGolier Prize for Academic Excellence (Box 20)
- Middle States Associations of Colleges and Secondary Schools, 1958-1979; (2 folders) (Box 20)
- Middle States, 1985-1987 (Box 20)
- Security (Box 20)
- Recruitment, 1985-1987 (Box 20)
- Minority and Special Students, 1984-1989 (Box 20)
- President's Distinguish Visitor and Exec. in Residence (Box 20)
- Nursery School Accreditation (Box 20)
- Student Complaints/Student-Faculty Relations, 1974-1987 (Box 20)
- Governance Revisions, 1981-1982 (Box 20)
- Staff Meetings, 1972-1978; (2 folders) (Box 20)
- SOS, 1983-1986 (Box 20)
- Middle Sates Statistics (Box 20)
- Vassar/Marist Consortium (Box 21)
- Master Copies, 1973-1974 (Box 21)
- Memorials/Services, 1982-1988 (Box 21)
- Middle States Reports, 1969-1985 (Box 21)
- Institutional Research, 1984 (Box 21)
- Board of Trustees Minutes, 1984-1987 (Box 21)
- Faculty Exchange (Box 21)
- EDUCOM (Box 21)
- Education Technology (Box 21)
- Chaplain-Committee for Review, 2 Oct 1980 (Box 21)
- Chinese American Educational Exchange, 8 Nov 1984 (Box 21)
- Chinese Visitors, 27 June 1986 (Box 21)
- Co-Education, 18 May 1984 (Box 21)
- College Court, 17 May 1982 (Box 21)
- Committee on Extracurricular Events, 26 Sep 1985 (Box 21)
- Confidentiality of Faculty Files, 8 Sep 1982 (Box 21)
- Conflict of Interest, 22 Sep 1983 (Box 21)
- Continuing Education, 13 May 1981 (Box 21)
- Convocation, 3 Sep 1986 (Box 21)
- Copyright Law, 1986 (Box 21)
- Council of Chief Academic Officers, 1980 (Box 21)
- Counseling and Testing Services, 1985 (Box 21)
- Annual Reports - Dean of the College, 1980-1983 (Box 21)
- Development Campaign, 1983 (Box 21)
- Equestrian Program, 1979 (Box 21)
- Founders Day, 1980 (Box 21)
- Graduate Program, 1983 (Box 21)
- Health Service, 1982 (Box 21)
- Holy Days, 1984 (Box 21)
- Hospitality, 1983 (Box 21)
- House Presidents, 1980 (Box 21)
- Housing and FAC Travel Forms, 1983 (Box 21)
- Inauguration, 1978 (Box 21)
- Institute on Writing, 1978 (Box 21)
- Institutional Review Board, 1983 (Box 21)
- Interdisciplinary Class of '83, 1983 (Box 21)
- Internal Revenue Service (Box 21)
- Inter-University Consortium for Political and Social Research, 1981 (Box 21)
- Keen Deans, 1980 (Box 21)
- Majors Committee, 1983 (Box 21)
- Maternity Benefits Committee, 1981 (Box 21)
- Micro Computer Resource Ctr, 1986 (Box 21)
- National Collegiate Athletic Assoc, 1985 (Box 21)
- National Education Association, 1982 (Box 21)
- NYS Council for Humanities, 1979 (Box 21)
- NYS Ed Dept-Certification-Elementary, 1975 (Box 21)
- NYS Ed Dept Non-collegiate Sponsored Instruction, 1977 (Box 21)
- NYS Ed Dept-Regents, 1983 (Box 21)
- NYS Ed Dept Title IX, 1979 (Box 21)
- NYS Ed Dept - Standard of Satisfactory Academic Progress, 1981 (Box 21)
- NYS Ed Dept Teacher Certification (Box 21)
- NYS The Governor's Committee on Scholastic Achievements, 1980 (Box 21)
- Notices, 1984-1986 (Box 21)
- Nuclear Symposium, 1982 (Box 21)
- Poynter Program, 1985 (Box 21)
- Procedures, 1982 (Box 21)
- Publications, 1985 (Box 21)
- Race Relations Task Force, 1986 (Box 21)
- Radio Station, 1972 (Box 21)
- Instructional Computing (Box 21)
- VC Junior Year Abroad, 1981 (Box 21)
- Faculty Counts, 1983-1985 (Box 21)
- NSF - Dean's File (Box 21)
- Accreditation - State (Box 21)
- NYS Ed Dept. Re: Amendments to Regulations, 1971 (Box 21)
- Eleanor Roosevelt Conference, 1985 (Box 22)
- Roosevelt Library, 1975 (Box 22)
- Rose, William K, Fellowship, 1981 (Box 22)
- Salary Reviews, 1986 (Box 22)
- Secretary of the Faculty, 1981-1983 (Box 22)
- Selective Service, 1971 (Box 22)
- Seven Seas Slide Show, 1983 (Box 22)
- Shell Companies Foundation, 1981 (Box 22)
- Sistm Quarterly, 1978 (Box 22)
- Smith, Virginia, President, 1977-1986 (Box 22)
- State Consumer Protection Board, 1979 (Box 22)
- Student Activities, 1983 (Box 22)
- Student Afro-American Society, 1986 (Box 22)
- Student Critic Interns, 1980 (Box 22)
- Student Handbook, 1984 (Box 22)
- Student Independent Production, 20 Oct 1982 (Box 22)
- Faculty Reviews, 1979-1981; (9 folders) (Box 22)
- Faculty Budget Recommendations, 1964-1965 (Box 22)
- Dept Recommendations [personnel], Apr 1971 (Box 22)
- Dept Recommendations [personnel], Oct 1967 (Box 22)
- FAC Minutes, Sep 1958 - Dec 1960 (Box 22)
- Research Committee, ca. 1960-1968; (5 folders) (Box 22)
- Research Committee, 1968 -; (12 folders) (Box 23)
- Vassar Library Dedication Committee (Box 23)
- Teacher Education Committee, (5 folders) (Box 23)
- Committee on the Vassar Journal of Undergraduate Studies (Box 23)
- Student Curriculum Committee, June 1959; (2 folders) (Box 23)
- Annual Reports, Feb 1917 - Jan 1950; (3 folders) (Box 23)
- Dean of Faculty Annual Reports, 1949-1967, 1970-1971; (5 folders) (Box 23)
- Dean of Faculty reports to Executive Committee, 1961-1969; (2 folders) (Box 23)
- Activities at the Urban Center, (2 folders) (Box 23)
- Reports to Trustees, 1962-1967, 1980-1983; (5 folders) (Box 24)
- "The 125th,", 1986 (Box 24)
- Unemployment Insurance, 1985 (Box 24)
- United Way, 1984 (Box 24)
- Urban Center, 1982 (Box 24)
- Union College, 1982 (Box 24)
- Vassar College - Oral History, 1972 (Box 24)
- Vassar Cooperative Bookshop, 1975 (Box 24)
- Vassar's German Summer, 1980 (Box 24)
- Vassar Jewish Students Union, 1984 (Box 24)
- Vassar Journalism Forum, 1985 (Box 24)
- Vassar/Trinity College Student Program, 1981 (Box 24)
- Vice President for Administrative and Student Services, 1985 (Box 24)
- Visas [personnel], 1977 (Box 24)
- Walker Field House, 1983 (Box 24)
- Weather, 1977 (Box 24)
- White House Fellows Program, 1979 (Box 24)
- Woodrow Wilson [Teacher] Fellowship, 1977 (Box 24)
- Wykeham Rise, 1980 (Box 24)
- Year Round Operation, 1973 (Box 24)
- Dept Chairman Handbook, 1982 (Box 24)
- Department Chairmen, 1983 (Box 24)
- Computer Facilities, 1982 (Box 24)
- German Summer Program - Vassar/William and Mary, 1981 (Box 24)
- Critical Languages Program, 1979-1985 (Box 24)
- Renaissance Studies, 1976 (Box 24)
- Pre Law, 1977 (Box 24)
- Pre Med, 1967-1981 (Box 24)
- Visual Arts Program, 1978 (Box 24)
- Huber Fund, 1982 (Box 24)
- Kennedy, Joseph Foundation, 1980 (Box 24)
- Lectures: All-College, 1981-1982, 1984-1985; (2 folders) (Box 24)
- Grants - American Chemical Society, 1981 (Box 24)
- Department of Energy Grant, 1980 (Box 24)
- Discretionary Grant Programs, 1977 (Box 24)
- FIPSE 81-84 Grant Proposal, 1981 (Box 24)
- Grants - Ford Foundation Requests, 1985 (Box 24)
- Energy Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 24)
- Energy Monitors (Box 24)
- Poynter Program (Box 24)
- British Teacher Program/ Woodrow Wilson National Fund (Box 24)
- British Teacher Program (Box 24)
- Committee on Committees (Box 24)
- Lectures - General (Box 24)
- Grants - GTE, 1982 (Box 25)
- Grants - General Service Foundation, 1980 (Box 25)
- Grants - Hew Educator, 1976 (Box 25)
- Grants - Hewlett Packard, 1983 (Box 25)
- Grants - Hoffman - La Roche, Inc., 1980 (Box 25)
- Grants - Howard Foundation (Brown University), 1979 (Box 25)
- Grants - National Institute of Arthritis, Metabolism and Digestive Diseases, 1979 (Box 25)
- Grants - Mudd Foundation, 1981 (Box 25)
- Grants - NYS Council on the Arts, 1980 (Box 25)
- Grants - Quill, 1980 (Box 25)
- Grant - Salmon Fund, 1982 (Box 25)
- Grants - S and H Foundation, 1983 (Box 25)
- Grants - Smithsonian, 1985 (Box 25)